Staff Room
Goodbye.
（日代(ひしろ)）失礼しました
Huh? Where's my bag?
あれ？ かばんが…
Wait...
（日代）というか 今
何か ものすごい音が
What was that noise?
〜♪
Overlap
（海崎(かいざき)）うっ… ん…
（すみれ）ん… 気がついた？
You're awake?
This is the nurse's office.
保健室よ
You two were found
collapsed by the stairs.
あなたたち 階段で倒れてたの
（海崎）うっ…
（すみれ）何があったの？
What happened?
Did you miss your step?
階段 踏み外した？
Yeah.
（海崎）
はい ちょっと 滑ったみたいで
I guess I sorta slipped.
Kaizaki-kun, you shielded
Kariu-san from the fall.
（すみれ）海崎君
狩生(かりう)さんをかばう形になってたわ
やるじゃない
さすが 男の子！
Nicely done.
Good boy.
* Actually 27
（海崎）ドスッ！
男の… 子…
Boy?
Inukai-sensei, Inukai-sensei,
please come to the staff room.
（教師）
えー… 犬飼(いぬかい)先生 犬飼先生
職員室までお願いします
（すみれ）
ん… ああ ごめんなさい
Oh, sorry.
I'll be back in a minute.
Can you stay with her?
先生 ちょっと行ってくるから—
狩生さんのそばに
いてあげてくれる？
Sure thing.
（海崎）分かりました
Oh, right.
Your classmate, Hishiro-san, let us know.
同じクラスの日代さんが
知らせてくれたのよ
She carried your stuff here, too.
あと あなたたちの荷物も
運んでくれたわ
Thank her later, okay?
今度 お礼を言っておきなさいね
Hishiro-san...
（海崎）日代さんが…
I knew it... that was Hishiro-san's.
（海崎）
やっぱり あれは 日代さんの
何で 狩生が持ってたんだろう
Why did Kariu have it?
What was she trying to do?
どうする気だったんだろう
She's got top sales again.
（男性社員）また あいつが
営業トップだとさ
We'll lose face if we let
a woman trounce us like this.
（男性社員）女に ここまで
やられちゃ 俺らの顔が立たねえよ
Why won't she just quit?
（男性社員）つか なかなか
辞めねえな あいつ
俺らのこと 気づいてないんかね？
Hasn't she worked it out yet?
With all we've done? She knows.
（男性社員）
いや あんだけやったら—
さすがに気づいてんじゃね？
（男性社員）おい お前ら
新人の前でやめろよ
Knock it off. The new guy's here.
Oh.
（男性社員）ああ 海崎の教育係
あいつだったっけ
She's in charge of his training, right?
Don't rat us out, Kaizaki.
（男性社員）
変な告げ口はすんなよ 海崎
I apologize.
（佐伯(さいき)）申し訳ありません
We'll make absolutely sure
nothing like this happens again.
今後 このようなミスはないように
気をつけますので—
Please, let us make it up to you.
なにとぞ
よろしくお願いいたします
You know this mess wasn't your fault!
（海崎）今回のミス
先輩のせいじゃないですよ 絶対！
We went over the order several times
この前 俺に やり方
教えてくれるために—
while you were showing me the ropes!
何度も 一緒に確認した
発注書じゃないですか！
Someone must've...
（海崎）きっと誰かが…
（佐伯）知ってる
I know.
Doesn't it make you mad?
怒ったりとか… しないんですか？
（佐伯）人を落とすことで 自分が
上がろうだなんて むなしいよ
Knocking others down to gain an advantage
is a fruitless endeavor.
そうすることでしか
勝ち目がないって—
It means they've given up
on winning any other way.
自分であきらめちゃってる
ってことだもん
At first,
みんなね…
we all competed fair and square.
It was really fun.
（佐伯）最初は 正々堂々
競い合って すごく楽しかった
But then,
なのに いつの間にか—
somehow we went from rivals to enemies.
ライバルじゃなくて
敵になっちゃった
Seeing hard workers turn out
like that doesn't make me mad.
（佐伯）怒るより何より—
頑張ってた人が そういうふうに
変わってしまうのを見るのは—
Just...
すごく 悲しい
...very sad.
Were you trying to bully her?
（海崎）嫌がらせしようとしたのか
A hard worker like you?
頑張り屋のお前が
Oh. Are you awake, Kariu?
（海崎）おっ 気がついたか 狩生
（海崎）おっ おい
あんま 急に動くな
Hey, no sudden movements.
Apparently, Hishiro-san found us
and let the teachers know.
日代さんが
先生に知らせてくれたらしい
I'm pretty sure she took that
green bag home with her.
緑のかばんは 多分
日代さんが持って帰ったんだと思う
That bag...
あのかばん やっぱり
日代さんのだったんだろ
It was Hishiro-san's, right?
Why did you have it?
何で 狩生が持ってた？
Don't run.
逃げるな
答えろ 狩生
Answer me, Kariu.
You steal anything?
（海崎）何か取ったのか？
（狩生）違う！
No!
No...
違う
少し… 困らせてやろうって
I just wanted to trouble her a bit...
どこかに 隠してやろうって
思っただけで…
I was gonna hide it somewhere.
Why?
（海崎）何で？
（狩生）えっ？
Why?
（海崎）何でだよ
Have you given up?
そんな嫌がらせを
することでしか もう—
日代さんには勝ち目がないって
あきらめたからか？
Do you think harassing her is
the only way you'll beat her?
So...
（狩生）言うの？
（海崎）ん？
Are you gonna tell her I tried to
harass her because I was jealous?
（狩生）あたしが
くだらない しっと心で—
嫌がらせをしようとしたって—
言うの？
You're close to her.
海崎 仲いいもんね
That's why you knew it was her bag,
だから あのかばんが
日代のだって気づいたし—
怒ってるんでしょ あたしのこと
and that's why you're mad at me.
I bet I could hurt you more if I told Oga.
日代さんよりも—
大神(おおが)に言ったほうが
ダメージでかそうで いいかもな
（狩生）ああっ あ… あ…
（海崎）うそだよ 言わねえよ
I'm kidding.
I won't do that.
ふう…
でも そういうことだと思うぞ
But... that is what I think.
Trying to knock others down a peg
just means lowering yourself.
人を落とそうとする行為は
結局 自分を落とす
Don't go trampling all the hard work
and trust you've built up.
今まで積み重ねてきた努力や信頼を
自分で踏みにじるな
It insults the effort you put in.
頑張ってきた自分に 失礼だ
The only way that would make you happy
そんなまねして
喜んでいられるのは—
is if you were a loser
who'd given up on trying.
もう 頑張ることをあきらめた
負け犬だ
But I don't think that describes you.
でも 俺は
狩生が そうだとは思えない
俺が知ってる狩生は
負けん気が強くて—
The Kariu I know hates losing,
is curt but kind,
ぶっきらぼうだけど 優しくて—
and is a hard worker with a strong heart.
芯の強い頑張り屋だと
Because I know how hard you've worked,
頑張る狩生を見てきたからこそ—
I'm not really mad. Just very, very sad.
怒るより何より
ただ ただ 悲しく思った
（海崎）汚い大人みたいなまね
しないでくれ
Don't act like some filthy adult.
You're still young!
まだ 若いんだ
頑張ることをあきらめな…
Don't give up on try—
何が分かるのよ！
What would you know?!
What the hell are you lecturing me for?
何 悟ったようなこと言ってんの？
同い年のくせに！
We're the same age!
I did try!
頑張ったわよ！
でも 全然 かなわない！
But I couldn't win.
かなわないどころか—
Not only that, they don't
even see me as a rival!
ライバルだとすら
認識してもらえてないのに！
Honoka for sports, Hishiro for studies...
（狩生）運動では ほのかに
勉強では 日代に！
I'm trying desperately to beat them!
あたしは こんなに必死なのに
何で ２人は涼しい顔で—
So why do they act like
I'm no threat at all?!
Why am I the only one with problems?!
何で あたしだけが
うまくいかないの？
I try and try and try and...
いくら頑張っても
頑張っても 頑張っても—
頑張って…
No matter how hard I try,
I get nothing in return.
頑張っても 結果が出ない
意味がない
It's all pointless.
そんなことない
That's not true.
周りと比べるから
見えにくいだけだ
You're just too busy comparing
yourself to others to see.
Those comparisons aren't the only measure.
人と比べた順位だけが
結果じゃない
Don't say it's all pointless.
意味ないなんて 否定するな
You've worked hard and made yourself better.
狩生は すげえ頑張って
その分 ちゃんと成長してる
That's what you got in return.
結果 出してる
So don't...
だから もう
こんなことして 自分を落とすな
...put yourself down like this.
（狩生）そっか あたし…
Oh...
I guess...
...all my hard work...
（狩生）ちゃんと頑張れてたんだ
...wasn't pointless.
意味なく… なかったんだ
Nurse's Office
Feeling better?
（海崎）落ち着いた？
はっ？ 何が？
Huh? About what?
Always gotta act tough, huh?
（海崎）強がるなあ ほんと
You said no matter how hard you tried...
狩生は
“いくら頑張っても”って言うけど
もう いいわよ その話は！
Stop talking about that!
But Hishiro-san's trying, too.
日代さんも 頑張ってると思う
She was in the staff room this late...
（海崎）こんな時間まで
職員室にいたって—
I bet she had questions
for the teachers.
それ 先生に
質問とかしてたんじゃないのか？
日代さんだって
うまくいかない部分 あるんだぞ
There are things even she doesn't find easy.
（日代）にたー…
She's really awkward, after all.
（海崎）不器用だからな
I think you've got the
wrong idea about her, too.
狩生は たぶん 日代さんを
誤解してる部分もあると思う
You've never really talked to her.
あんまり ちゃんと話したこと
ないだろ？
Oh, right!
ああ そうだ
Next time you get a chance,
ask her to smile for you.
今度 機会があったら
“笑ってみて”って言ってみ
Smile?
笑って？
It's really something.
面白い子だよ
（海崎）うわあ…
説教たれちまった
I just lectured her like an old man!
オッサンくせえ！
Don't give up on trying.
“頑張ることを
あきらめないでくれ”
Talk about pot calling the kettle black.
なんつうブーメランだよ
I'm one to talk,
considering I gave up.
よくもまあ
あきらめたやつが偉そうに
Wh-What's up, Hishiro-san?
どっ どうしたの？ 日代さん
I was waiting for you.
（日代）海崎さんを待ってました
There's something bothering me.
（日代）どうしても
気になったことがあって—
考えても分からなくて—
Thinking about it didn't get me anywhere,
so I waited to ask you.
聞きたくて 待ってました
どうして—
Why did Kariu-san have my bag?
狩生さんが 私のかばんを
持っていたんでしょうか？
I've thought about it a lot,
（日代）
いろいろ考えましたが—
正直 “取られた”という
答えしか出てこなくて—
but all I can think of is that
she stole it, so I'm confused.
困惑しています
Uh...
Kariu-san and my eyes
have been meeting often lately,
狩生さんとは 最近
よく目が合うし—
and every time, I've made sure to smile.
目が合えば 笑いかけるよう
心がけていて—
So I thought we were friendly.
仲良くなれていってるものだと
思っていたので
Th-Think!
（海崎）か… 考えろ
What the hell should I tell this
malice-free tone-deaf communicator?!
この 一切 悪気のない
超コミュ音痴に—
何て答えるのが正解なんだ！
Sh-She thought it was dangerous
to leave the bag lying in the hall.
廊下にかばんを放っておくのは
危ないって思ったんだと…
So she thought she'd take care of it for you.
それで とりあえず
保護しておこうと 狩生が
そうですか
それならよかったです
Oh...
That's a relief.
Now that I know the reason,
I feel a lot better.
理由が分かって すっきりしました
I knew she couldn't have tried to steal it.
取るだなんて—
そんなはずないと
思ったんです
But I couldn't think of anything else.
I'm ashamed of myself.
でも 他に考えが
及ばなかった自分が—
恥ずかしいです
Is getting rid of all the thorns in
someone's path really what's best for them?
（夜明(よあけ)）石をどけた きれいな道を
歩かせてあげることが—
はたして
本人のためになるのかどうか
Sorry.
ごめん 今のは うそだ
That was a lie.
Kariu took your bag to
cause problems for you.
（海崎）狩生は 日代さんの
かばんを持ち逃げして—
困らせようとした
Why would she...
なぜ そんな…
シルバーピンが欲しかったから—
She wanted the silver pin,
しっととか 悔しさとか…
so she was jealous and frustrated.
Kariu-san wants this?
狩生さんは
これが欲しいということでしょうか
Holy crap.
（海崎）やばい 大神以上の鈍感
She's even denser than Oga.
では これをあげたら
友達になれますか？
Then if I give her this,
can we be friends?
（海崎）ねえよ
（日代）あ…
No way.
I don't understand.
分からないです
Does Kariu-san hate me?
私 狩生さんから
憎まれてるんですか？
Yeah, I guess you wouldn't get it.
まあ 日代さんには
分かんねえだろうな
（日代）グサッ
（女子生徒）日代さんさあ
Hishiro-san,
いくら 頭良くても
その鈍感さは どうかと思うよ
for someone so smart,
you can be really dense.
You haven't noticed that
everyone's mad at you, have you?
みんながイラついてるの
気づいてないでしょ
何を言ったら怒るとか—
I don't understand what I say
that makes people so mad.
人の気持ちとか そういうのが
全然 分からないんです
I don't understand how they feel.
I know that's because
I haven't properly socialized.
ちゃんと 人付き合いを
してこなかったせいだと—
自覚しています
I've tried to learn.
学ぼうと 私なりに
調べたりもするんですけど—
I've tried to study up on it,
一体 何が正解なのか
but I just don't know what's right.
うーん 難しいよな
That's a tough one.
There is no right answer for getting along.
人付き合いに
決まった正解なんてないし—
Different people require different answers.
相手が違えば
正解も違うだろうし
Different people...
require different answers?
（日代）
相手が違えば 正解も違う？
（海崎）ごめん
悩ませるつもりは…
Sorry, I didn't mean to overload you.
I'm going to wait for Kariu-san.
（日代）
私 狩生さんを待ちます
（海崎）えっ
（日代）このままでは 嫌です
I can't leave this be.
私 ちゃんと 狩生さんと
友達になりたいです
I want to be her friend for real.
But I don't know how.
でも どうしたらいいのか
分かりません
正解も解き方も分からないなら
直接 聞きます
If I don't know the right answer...
I'll just ask her.
Like you're asking a teacher?
（海崎）んなっ…
先生に質問するみたいなノリで？
One more question.
あと １つ 聞きたいことが
When I saw your hands wrapped
protectively around her,
（日代）狩生さんをかばう
海崎さんの手を見た時に—
気持ちが もやっとしたのは
なぜ？
why did I feel a pang?
No, never mind.
いえ やっぱりいいです
一度に 多くの問題を抱えるのは
効率が悪い
It's ineffective to deal
with many problems at once.
まずは １つずつ
One at a time.
Please go home.
海崎さんは お帰りください
I think I have to take care of this myself.
自分で何とかしなければ
ならないことだと思いますので
G-Got it.
（海崎）わ 分かった
See you later, then.
じゃあ… お先に
As if!
（海崎）って！
こんな状況 放って帰れるかー！
Like I can possibly just leave!
Will she be okay?
大丈夫かなあ？
（夜明）大丈夫ですかねえ？
I dunno, will she?
Why are you here?!
（海崎）何で いる！
（夜明）今さら変なこと言いますね
You should be used to this by now.
海崎さんのいる所
常に 僕ありですよ
Wherever you go, I go with you.
（海崎）キメえ！
（夜明）声 大きいですって
Creepy!
Keep your voice down!
あと“キモい”は
ひどいです
And don't be mean.
You're supposed to be
watching me, not Hishiro.
あんたの役目は
日代さんじゃなくて俺の観察だろう
The influence your choices
have on those around you
海崎さんの選択が
周囲に与える影響
is also a target of my observations.
その行く末
それもまた 観察対象ですので
（日代）
狩生さん 待ってました
Kariu-san.
I've been waiting for you.
An ambush?
（狩生）待ち伏せ？
Oh. that's right.
あっ そっか
あたしが 日代のかばんを
持ってたことは バレてるんだっけ
She knows I had her bag.
So this is an interrogation.
ってことは 尋問…
（日代）狩生さん
（狩生）はっ…
Kariu-san.
そんなに このシルバーピンが
欲しいんですか？
Do you want this silver pin that badly?
Right for the jugular!
（海崎･夜明）
いきなり あおった！
（日代）
狩生さんが 私のかばんを—
I heard you tried to run off with my bag.
持ち逃げしようとしたことを
聞きました
Kaizaki-san told me.
海崎さんから
（狩生）あいつ！
That jerk!
（海崎）
俺の告げ口 バラされたー！
She ratted me out for ratting Kariu out!
When I asked why you would do that,
（日代）なぜ そんなことを
したのかと聞いたら—
シルバーピンが理由だと
he said your motive was this silver pin.
So I asked if we could
be friends if I gave you this,
じゃあ これを譲れば
友達になれるかと聞いたら—
“ねえよ”と言われました
and he said no way.
（狩生）ないわ
Yeah, no way.
狩生さん
Kariu-san.
Do you hate me?
私のことが お嫌いですか？
Not really...
別に そんな…
I...
Then why did you take my bag?
では なぜ かばんを？
嫌いではない相手に
そのような行動を起こす意図は？
Why would you do that
to someone you don't hate?
She straight up asked.
（海崎）どストレート
よくも まあ
ああも ずけずけ聞けるな
I dunno how she can keep asking this stuff.
自分の心 えぐられねえのかな？
Doesn't it hurt her?
日代さんですからねえ
Well, it is Hishiro-san.
No, I...
別に…
（海崎）逃げるな
Don't run.
答えろ 狩生
Answer, Kariu.
I'm not...
（狩生）
誰が… もう 逃げるか！
...running anymore!
I hate you.
（狩生）嫌いよ
（日代）あ…
（狩生）どれだけ頑張っても
かなわなくて—
No matter how hard I try, I can't win.
あたしが欲しかったものを
手に入れて—
You took what I wanted.
あたしが欲しかった場所を
手に入れて！
You stood where I wanted to.
And ever since you won, you've always,
勝ち誇ったように いつも—
いつも あたしをバカにして笑う
あんたが 大っ嫌いよ！
always flashed that mocking smile,
so of course I hate you!
（日代）
バカになんてしたことないです
I've never mocked you.
してるじゃない！
目が合うたびに いつもいつも
You do! Every time our eyes meet!
（日代）してません
（狩生）してる！
I don't.
You do!
Why would I ever do that?
なぜ 私が
狩生さんをバカにする必要が…
（狩生）知るか！
Don't ask me!
（狩生）
何 すっとぼけてるのよ！
How can you deny it?!
あんなに 何度も
人を こけにしておいて
That constant stream of sneers...
目が合うたびに
話すたびに いつもいつも！
Every time our eyes meet,
every time we speak!
今度 機会があったら
“笑ってみて”って言ってみ
Next time you get a chance,
ask her to smile for you.
（狩生）まさか…
Wait...
（狩生）日代 ちょっと笑ってみて
Hishiro...
Smile for me.
Where did that come from?
何ですか？ 急に
待ってください
Hold on. I'm trying to think
of a reason I'd mock—
今 私が狩生さんをバカにする
理由を考えているところ…
（狩生）いいから！
Just do it!
人と目が合った時に ニコッとする
程度の笑顔でいいから！
A normal smile, like you'd do
if your eyes met someone's!
Like this?
こうですか？
（日代）今 引きましたよね？
You just freaked out.
（狩生）えっ？ あっ いや
ちょっ… 待って 整理する
Huh?
Er... wait... let me get this straight.
（狩生）えっ？ えっ？
今のが 日代の中での笑顔？
Huh? Huh?
Hishiro thinks that's a smile?!
She was trying for a friendly smile.
あの子
あれで愛想笑いのつもりなんだ
I thought Kaizaki was lying.
（狩生）てっきり
海崎のうそだと思ってたのに
（狩生）もう１回 笑ってみて
Smile again.
Stop.
戻して
Again.
（狩生）もう１回
（日代）へへ…
この どヘタクソ！
Oh my god, you suck!
How is that a smile?!
それの どこが笑顔よ！
鏡 見たことあんの!?
Have you even looked in a mirror?!
そんな笑顔 無言で向けられた人が
どう思うと思ってんのよ！
Do you have any idea
how it makes people feel?!
あたし てっきり バカに
されてるんだと ずっと思ってた！
I thought you were
mocking me this whole time!
I have been smiling in the hope
that we could be friends.
私は ずっと—
狩生さんと友達になりたい一心で
笑ってました
（狩生）何 この子
Wow, this girl...
どんだけ不器用なのよ
How awkward can you be?
私の長所は 頭がいいところです
My strong point is I'm smart.
（日代）分からないところがあれば
自分で調べ—
If I don't understand something,
それでも分からなければ質問し
解決に努めます
I look into it on my own,
and if I still don't get it, I ask until I do.
My weak point is that
I'm not interested in other people.
短所は
周囲に全く興味がないことです
（海崎･夜明）
言い切った！
She said it!
Because of that, I don't know
how to interact with anyone,
（日代）そのせいで
人との付き合い方が分からず—
おそらく 多くの人に
迷惑をかけてきました
and I must have caused
lots of problems for people.
だけど 今は こんな自分を
変えていきたいと思っています
But right now, I'm trying to change myself.
狩生さん こんな私ですが—
Kariu-san, that's who I am.
友達になって… くれませんか？
But would you be my friend?
It's my pleasure, Hishiro Chizuru-san.
よろしくね 日代千鶴(ちづる)さん
That day,
（狩生）あの時
あれも 別に 握手を
避けられたわけじゃなかったんだ
she wasn't intentionally
ignoring the handshake.
Okay, Hishiro Chizuru-san.
よろしく 日代千鶴さん
でも そのかわり！
But in return, recognize me as your rival!
あたしのこと ライバルだって
ちゃんと認めてよね！
次は負けないから
I won't lose next time!
絶対 あたしが
シルバーピンを取ってみせるから！
I'll definitely take that silver pin from you!
そんなに欲しいなら
次のテストで お譲りしますが
If you want it, you can have it next test...
（狩生）そうじゃないんだって！
欲しいけど そうじゃない
Don't you dare! I want it, but not like that!
手加減なんかしたら
即 絶交してやる！
If you hold back, we're not friends!
Not Friends
And...
（狩生）あと…
I'm really sorry about all this.
今回のことは
本当に ごめんなさい
I won't do it again.
もう 二度としない
Sorry.
ごめん
（日代）許します
I forgive you.
友達… ですから
After all, we're friends.
なんだ ちゃんと笑えるんじゃない
Whoa, so you can actually smile.
（日代）いつだって笑えてますが
But I smile all the time.
（狩生）うそつけ！
Yeah, right!
You told Hishiro about me.
But thanks.
What'd you take a picture for?
何 撮ってる？
ＪＫにLIME(ライム)もらって
にやける被験者
A test subject grinning
because a high school girl LIMEd him.
報告書用に
For my report.
Delete it!
（海崎）消せ！ 大体 何で
俺ん家(ち)で飲んでんだよ
Why are we drinking at my place, anyway?
何 これ！
What is all this?!
いいじゃないですか
What's the big deal?
海崎さんが ２人の仲を取り持った
めでたい日でしょう？
You helped them become friends.
Let's celebrate!
ん… 明日も学校なんだぞ
We've got school tomorrow.
ニートやってた割に
まじめなんですよねえ 海崎さん
For an ex-NEET, you sure are serious.
（海崎）
ニートじゃねえ フリーター！
Not NEET! I was a part-timer!
Yoake-san...
夜明さん
Was what I told Kariu
really the right thing to say?
俺が 狩生にかけた言葉は
正しかったんだろうか
Resignation
だって 現実は—
In reality, I couldn't grow up,
and became a NEET.
大人になりきれなかった
甘い俺が ニートになり—
他人を落としたあいつらは たぶん
今も 悠々と仕事を続けてる
And those awful bullies probably
still have their jobs.
I know the real truth is uglier.
我ながら
きれい事を吐いたなあと
確かに
きれい事だったかもしれません
Maybe it wasn't the ugly truth.
でも うそじゃない
But it wasn't a lie.
本心から出た言葉なんだから
いいじゃないですか
It's what you really meant,
so isn't that enough?
狩生さんが 社会に出て
つまずいた時—
When she's out in the
real world and stumbles,
誰とは思い出せないけど 自分を
しかってくれた人がいたなあと—
she'll remember someone
yelling at her, if not who.
今日の記憶は きっと彼女の中に
残り続けるんじゃないかと思います
I think what happened today
will stay with her.
そっか
Oh.
Though, really, it was
the pot calling the kettle black!
まあ 盛大なブーメラン
投げてるなとは思いましたが
“人と比べた順位だけが
結果じゃない”？
Yelling at her for comparing
herself to others!
周囲との差に焦って—
Says the man so worried about appearances,
he pretended he still had a job!
仕事してるフリしてた人が
よく言いますわ
（海崎）グサッ
うっせえ！
ちゃんと 自分でも思ったわ！
Shut up! I thought the same thing!
どうです？ リライフ
So? Are you liking ReLIFE?
自分を いい感じで
見つめ直せてます？
Is it letting you take a long,
hard look at yourself?
その 何でもお見通し感が
ほんっと ムカつくわーっ！
The way you see through everything
is seriously driving me nuts!
Rena, see any empty seats?
（玉来(たまらい)）玲奈(れな)
空いてる席 あった？
Say, Honoka...
ほのか あのさ
〜♪
Thanks for the food.
いただきます
〜♪
おっ お昼
一緒に食べてあげてもいいけど
I-I don't mind eating lunch with you.
別に大丈夫です
私 １人 好きですし
I'm fine like this.
I like being alone.
それがダメなんでしょ！
変わりたいんでしょ！
Isn't that the problem?!
Don't you want to change?!
（日代）そうでした
That's right.
Then, please.
では お願いします
ありがとうございます
Thank you.
おっ お礼なんかいいのよ
D-Don't thank me!
We're friends!
友達なんだから！
普通なんだから！
This is normal!
NEXT EPISODE
（狩生）日代は まず
笑顔の練習からね
Hishiro, you need to first
practice how to smile.
（日代）にやあ…
（狩生）だからそうじゃないってば
Grin.
Not like that.
（日代）
できてるつもりですが
But I thought I was doing it right.
狩生さん
手本を見せてください
Show me how it's done, Kariu-san.
（狩生）えっ？ 仕方ないなあ
Huh? Oh, all right.
This Isn't the First Time
（狩生）キッ… キラッ
（日代）カタいですね
H-Heh.
How stiff.
（狩生）
あんたに言われたくないわよ！
I don't wanna hear that from you!